我们来谈谈对象特征。
Let’s talk about object features.
我们已经讨论过描述一个物体的位置。
We’ve already talked about describing the position of an object.
我们已经研究了如何描述对象的质心，这是一种有用的描述方式
We’ve worked out how to describe the centroid of an object, which is a useful way of describing
什么东西在图像中。
where something is within the image.
我们还谈到了确定一个物体的大小-它的面积-我们可以
We’ve also talked about determining the size of an object—its area—and we can
从第0个时刻获得这些信息。
get that information from the zeroth moments.
我们可能有兴趣描述一个物体的形状;它看起来像鲨鱼，或者
We might be interested to describe the shape of an object; does it look like a shark, or
三角形，圆形或正方形，我们可能有兴趣描述方向
a triangle, or a circle, or a square, and we might be interested in describing the orientation
对象。
of the object.
这非常重要。
It’s quite important.
鲨鱼是向上，向左还是向右？
Is the shark pointing upwards, or to the left or to the right?
那么让我们来谈谈我们如何计算其中一些额外的对象特性。
So let’s talk about how we can compute some of these additional object features.
我们已经根据边界框和质心描述了这个位置
Position we’ve already described in terms of the bounding box and the centroid, which
源自最初的时刻。
is derived from first moments.
对象的大小;我们也把它称为它的区域，它可以用第0个来描述
The size of the object; we also call it its area, and it can be described form the zeroth
时刻。
moments.
到目前为止我们还没有描述的是形状和方向，所以让我们谈谈这个问题。
What we haven’t described so far is shape and orientation, so let’s talk about that.
我们要做的就是使用一种称为等效椭圆的技术。
The way we’re going to do this is to use a technique called the equivalent ellipse.
因此，对于这些形状中的每一个，我们要做的是考虑一个居中的椭圆
So for each of these shapes what we’re going to do is to consider an ellipse that is centred
在物体的质心处，对于那个质心，它具有相同的惯性矩
at the object’s centroid, and that has got the same moment of inertia about that centroid
原来的形状有。
as the original shape has.
所以这意味着对于这些不同种类的形状，我们将会得到不同的形状
So this means for these different kinds of shapes we’re going to get different shaped
等效的椭圆，他们会告诉我们关于形状和形状的东西
equivalent ellipses and they’re going to tell us something about the shape and the
对象的方向。
orientation of the object.
这是一种非常经典的技术，但它实际上非常有用。
This is quite a classical technique, but it’s actually quite useful.
让我们付诸实践。
Let’s put it into practice.
这是我们的鲨鱼形象。
Here is our shark image.
这是质心。
Here’s the centroid.
我们将定义一组正交轴;穿过的x轴和y轴
We’re going to define a set of orthogonal axes; an x-axis and a y-axis that pass through
鲨鱼的质心，它们与u和v坐标平行。
the centroid of the shark, and they’re parallel to the u and v coordinates.
现在，一旦我有了这个坐标系，就可以很容易地计算出惯性矩阵
Now once I’ve got this coordinate system, it’s easy to compute the inertia matrix
围绕质心的y轴和x轴周围的斑点。
for the blob around the y and x axes about the centroid.
我们通过计算所谓的blob的中心矩来做到这一点：mu，下划线，
And we do that by computing what are called the central moments of the blob: mu, underscore,
P，Q。
p,q.
这与我们之前的表达式非常相似，除了括号内部
And this is very similar to the moment expression we had earlier, except inside the brackets
我们现在减去质心的坐标。
we now subtract the coordinates of the centroid.
因此，如果我们计算这些时刻：mu，2,0，mu，0,2和mu，1,1为blob我们最终得到一个矩阵
So if we compute these moments: mu,2,0, mu,0,2 and mu,1,1 for the blob we end up with a matrix
包含惯性值。
that contain the inertia values.
我们想要找到一个椭圆，它具有与我们从中得到的惯性相同的惯性
We want to find an ellipse that has got the same inertia as those we derived from the
斑点。
blob.
现在，如果这是惯性矩阵，我们可以计算其特征值，并从那些特征值计算
Now if this is the inertia matrix we can compute its eigenvalues, and from those eigenvalues
我们可以计算椭圆的长轴和短轴。
we can compute the major and minor axis of the ellipse.
这基本上是椭圆长轴的一半，也是椭圆短轴的一半。
That’s basically half the long axis of the ellipse, and half the short axis of the ellipse.
这些半径a和b是从矩阵J的特征值导出的.Lambda1是最大的特征值，
These radii a and b are derived from the eigenvalues of the matrix J. Lambda 1 is the largest eigenvalue,
和lambda2是较小的特征值。
and lambda 2 is the smaller eigenvalue.
我们也对椭圆的方向感兴趣;什么是θ的价值。
We’re also interested in the orientation of the ellipse; what’s the value of θ.
并且我们从特征向量的元素中获得对应于最大元素的θ
And we obtain θ from the elements of the eigenvector that corresponds to the largest
特征值。
eigenvalue.
因此我们采用特征向量中的两个元素的比率，即反正切
So we take the ratio of the two elements in the eigenvector, the arc tangent, and that
给我们θ。
gives us θ.
这告诉我们椭圆的方向，椭圆的方向告诉我们
That tells us the orientation of the ellipse, and the orientation of the ellipse tells us
关于物体本身的方向的东西。
something about the orientation of the object itself.
我们可以从等效椭圆得到的另一个有用的参数是
Another parameter that’s useful that we can derive from the equivalent ellipse is
称为宽高比，即b/a。
called the aspect ratio, that’s b/a.
B是短长度，a是长长度，b/a总是小于1。
B is the short length, a is the long length, b/a is always less than 1.
它说明了形状的紧凑性。
And it says something about the compactness of the shape.
例如，这条鲨鱼的比例大约为1，大约是1
So this shark, for instance, has got a ratio of b over a that’s roughly 1, where this
鲨鱼的值b/a比1小得多。
shark has got a value b/a that’s much smaller than 1.
所以b/a说明了形状的紧凑性。
So b/a says something about the compactness of the shape.
让我们加载鲨鱼图像的另一种变体，我们将显示它。
Let’s load yet another variant of our shark image, and we will display this.
在这里，我们看到两条鲨鱼，一条向下倾斜，一条向上倾斜。
And here we see two sharks, one pitched downwards, and one pitched a little bit upwards.
我们将使用熟悉的命令计算这些blob的参数，我们会看到
We will compute the parameters of these blobs using a familiar command to us, and we see
我们发现了三个斑点：两个鲨鱼斑点和一个背景斑点。
we’ve found three blobs: two shark blobs and one background blob.
让我们简化事情并摆脱背景blob，因为我们真的只是
Let’s simplify things and get rid of the background blob, since we’re really only
对鲨鱼对象感兴趣。
interested in the shark objects.
我们再次使用iblobs功能;传递图像。
We use the iblobs function again; pass in the image.
我们只要求那些包含属于1类像素的blob;就这样
And we ask for just those blobs comprising pixels that belong to class 1; that is, that
颜色1它们是场景中的白色像素。
the colour 1 they are the white pixels within the scene.
现在我们有一个blob对象数组，但只有那些在白色内的白色对象
And now we have an array of blob objects but only those objects that are white within the
场景：两条鲨鱼。
scene: the two sharks.
在显示每个blob的地方，我们会看到这些blob的许多参数或属性，
Where each blob is displayed we see a number of parameters or attributes of those blobs,
其中一些现在非常熟悉。
and some of those are quite familiar to use now.
例如，区域和质心。
For instance, the area and the centroid.
参数θ是斑点的方向。
The parameter θ is the orientation of the blob.
方位是以弧度为单位给出的，它是相对于附加的坐标系
Orientation is given in unit of radians, and it is in respect to a coordinate frame attached
到与u轴和v轴平行的鲨鱼。
to the shark that’s parallel to the u and v axes.
顺时针方向的方向为正。
An orientation is positive in the clockwise direction.
我们可以看到一只鲨鱼的θ值为29而另一只鲨鱼的θ值为
We can see that one shark has got a θ value of 29 and the other shark has a θ value of
-2.58，所以这表明它们有不同的方向。
-2.58, so this suggests that they have different orientations.
这里的另一个参数是比率b/a，我们将其称为纵横比。
Another parameter here is the ratio b/a, and we refer to that as the aspect ratio.
这里有趣的是两条鲨鱼的长宽比相同，
And what’s interesting here is that the two sharks have got the same aspect ratio,
大约0.585，或0.586，这是重要和有趣的，因为纵横比是
around about 0.585, or 0.586 and this is important and interesting because the aspect ratio is
即使鲨鱼有不同的位置和不同的方向，所以我们
the same even though the sharks have got different positions and different orientations, so we
将其称为形状不变量。
refer to this as a shape invariant.
它是鲨鱼的一个特征，它独立于它的位置或方向。
It’s a characteristic of the shark and it’s independent of its position or its orientation.
现在我们已经讨论了等效的椭圆，这很容易
Now we’ve talked a bit before about the equivalent ellipse, and it’s pretty easy
情节。
to plot.
我们将绘图椭圆方法应用于鲨鱼斑点的矢量，这将是绘图
We apply the plot ellipse method to the vector of shark blobs, and what this will do is plot
该向量的每个元素的等效椭圆，向量中的所有对象
an equivalent ellipse for every element of that vector, all of the objects in the vector
b，在这里我们看到绘制了两个等效的椭圆。
b, and here we see the two equivalent ellipses plotted.
我们可以使用绘图方法几乎一样容易地绘制质心，应用于每个对象
We can plot the centroids almost as easily using the plot method, applied to every object
在向量b中。
in the vector b.
因此，总结一下我们可以为blob派生的对象特征。
So to summarise the object features that we can derive for a blob.
我们可以用边界框或质心来描述它的位置。
We can describe its position in terms of bounding box or centroid.
我们可以确定它的大小，面积。
We can determine its size, its area.
我们可以看一下它的形状，它来自等效椭圆的纵横比，
We can look at its shape and that comes from the aspect ratio of the equivalent ellipse,
我们可以从等效的方向确定对象的方向
and we can determine the orientation in the object from the orientation of the equivalent
椭圆。
ellipse.